<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <title>Watershed Administrative Units</title>
                <onlink>https://gis.dnr.wa.gov/site2/rest/services/Public_Forest_Practices/WADNR_PUBLIC_FP_Watershed/MapServer/0</onlink>
                <onlink>https://fortress.wa.gov/dnr/adminsa/gisdata/datadownload/state_wau.zip</onlink>
                <onlink>https://fortress.wa.gov/dnr/adminsa/gisdata/metadata/wau.htm</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>As established by WAC 222-22-020, the state is divided into areas known as watershed administrative units (WAUs). WAU boundaries are defined by the Department of Natural Resources (DNR) in cooperation with the departments of Ecology, Fish and Wildlife, affected Indian tribes, local governments, forest land owners, and the public. This dataset is intended for use at 1:24,000 scale. WAU's are used by the Timber/Fish/Wildlife cooperators as the boundaries for watershed analysis studies and other natural resources management purposes on state and privately owned lands.    WAU represents the administrative boundaries of 846 units. The boundaries are mainly along drainage divides (ridges), with some along rivers and other Washington State Department of Natural Resources (DNR) management boundaries. In the forested areas of the state WAUs range in size from 3,822 to 297,614 acres with a mean of 40,187 acres and a standard deviation of 26,697 acres. On the Columbia Plateau WAU areas range in size from 35,098 to 1,765,555 acres.  This version of the WAU boundaries is current as of April 2006.   Administrative boundaries based on hydrology form a general hierarchy. Water Resource Inventory Areas (WRIAs) are the largest unit, BASINs are subunits of WRIAs, and WAUs are subunits of BASINs. However, boundaries in this hierarchy do not necessarliy match in all areas.  Where watershed analysis was been conducted, WAU boundaries may cross WRIA lines.  Do not use WAU to derive WRIA boundaries. WRIA is managed and maintained by the Washington Department of Ecology.</abstract>
            <purpose>Watershed Administrative Units</purpose>
        </descript>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>DNR</themekey>
                <themekey>WAU</themekey>
                <themekey>watershed</themekey>
                <themekey>watershed analysis</themekey>
                <themekey>watershed administrative unit</themekey>
                <themekey>hydrography</themekey>
                <themekey>Forest Practices</themekey>
                <themekey>Washington Department of Natural Resources</themekey>
            </theme>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>None</accconst>
        <useconst>DisclaimerThe Washington State Department of Natural Resources (DNR)
provides these geographic data &amp;quot;as is.&amp;quot; DNR makes no guarantee or
warranty concerning the accuracy of information contained in the geographic
data. DNR further makes no warranties, either expressed or implied as to any
other matter whatsoever, including, without limitation, the condition of the
product, or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for determining
fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these data have been processed
successfully on computers of DNR, no warranty, expressed or implied, is made by
DNR regarding the use of these data on any other system, nor does the fact of
distribution constitute or imply any such warranty. In no event shall the DNR
have any liability whatsoever for payment of any consequential, incidental,
indirect, special, or tort damages of any kind, including, but not limited to,
any loss of profits arising out of use of or reliance on the geographic data or
arising out of the delivery, installation, operation, or support by DNR.

WA ISB, IT Security, Data Category 1 - Public Information (See Security Information). External requests for this data should be directed to the WA DNR GIS Data Center web site (http://www.dnr.wa.gov/BusinessPermits/Topics/Data/Pages/gis_data_center.aspx).</useconst>
        <datacred>Washington State Department of Natural Resources Forest Practices Division
Point of contact:
Contact information:
Contact organization primary:
Contact person: 
Contact organization: Washington State Department of Natural Resources
Contact position: Hydrography and Transportation Data Steward


Contact address:
Address type: mailing address
Address:
P.O. Box 47012
City: Olympia
State or province: WA
Postal code: 98504-7012
Country: U.S.A.

Contact voice telephone: 360-902-1403
Contact facsimile telephone: 360-902-1428

Contact electronic mail address: @dnr.wa.gov</datacred>
    </idinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20170314</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
